Guide to the New Orleans Collection 1770-1904 (bulk 1804-1836) MS 1944
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series X. Police Department Reports, 1808-1825
  - Garde de Ville, reports, 1808-1809, 1818, 1823-1825 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Series XI. Fire Department Rosters, 1861-1862 (bulk Oct. 1862)
  In English. This series contains "Paroles of Honor" for the Fireman's Charitable Association and rosters of various companies, many of which include records of oaths of allegiance to the U.S., aliens and enemies.
  - Fireman's Charitable Association, company rosters, 1861-[1862] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Various company rosters, Sept.-Oct. 1862, [1862] (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Series XII. Medical Reports, 1813, 1817, 1830
  Bulk in English. Reports of the Charity Hospital and the Orleans Infirmary; physician reports from the yellow fever epidemic of 1817 (includes daily tallies of cases).
  - Reports, Charity Hospital, Orleans Infirmary, 1813, 1830 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Reports, yellow fever, 1817 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series XIII. Correspondence, 1805-1879, 1904
  French and English. This series contains miscellaneous correspondence, some of which is personal in nature, regarding legislation, finances, business matters. Also included are letters to officials of the city of Lafayette concerning city limits, ferries, fire engines.
  - City of Lafayette, 1833-1838 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1805-1879, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Series XIV. Freemason Documents, 1868
  In French. Nominations for membership, resignation.
  - Freemasons, 1868 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Series XV. Education Records: Invoices for School Books, 1841, 1848
  In English. Bills of lading/invoices for books ordered by public schools, Second Municipality.
  - Invoices for school books, 1841, 1848 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series XVI. Poem, undated
  In French. One anonymous poem entitled "Enfants du Sud."
  - Poem, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series XVII. Military Certificate, 1859
  In English. Certificate appointing L.D. Nicholls Jr. First Lieutenant, Militia of Louisiana.
  - Military certificate, 1859 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series XVIII. Railroad Images, undated
  Reproductions (clippings) of photos of railroad engines.
  - Railroad images, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series XIX. Fragments, undated
  Mostly blank paper.
  - Fragments, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)